# Alejandro Rodriguez

Los Angeles, CA | av.rodriguez@outlook.com | (805) 663-3519

#### **SUMMARY**

Analytical, creative, solution-based professional with five years of experience in the Tech Industry, two in B2B SaaS Sales. Track record of successful software sales, optimizing company practices, and understanding client issues to provide better solutions. Eager to leverage extensive sales experience along with acquired software engineering skills to provide valuable solutions that impact the world.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools: Salesforce, Hubspot, LinkedIn Sales Navigator, and ZoomInfo.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Full Stack Developer Student | CodingDojo | Los Angeles, CA.

2022

- 3000+ hours of programming during the camp, mastering high-quality code, debugging, and optimizing old code.
- Developed several full CRUD applications using different programming languages and stacks.
- Led our last app as a SCRUM master, delivering our library app on time and with efficient code.
- Employed and used several APIs to give my apps a unique user experience.

# Sales Development Representative (SDR) | ShipERP | Long Beach, CA

2019-2022

- Pioneered software sales expansion into Latin America, increasing company sales by 18% through breaking language barriers
  of communication and optimizing client's supply chain with our solution written in ABAP using SAP's Api.
- Lead communications with clients and prospects, understanding the current issues and needs to report these findings to the team, improving product efficiency and corrections.
- Represented the company at National SAP and Software Conferences and Events.
- Managed, outreached, and qualified a high volume of inbound leads.
- Maintained active engagement with prospects, exceeding monthly quotas and ensuring lead satisfaction.

## **Sales Development Representative** | *Hacienda Furniture* | Oxnard, CA.

2018-2019

- Boosted sales and delivery times by suggesting renting a new warehouse in a strategic location that allowed us to have more inventory and mobility of our furniture.
- Increased efficiency on delivery times by scheduling one-day deliveries based on the client's location, taking advantage of our warehouse system.
- Upgraded data capture since the company was still using paper. Utilized new software for the company and started capturing data more efficiently. Boosted sales and qualifying leads and established better communication between teams.

## Founding Member | Vinik | Mexico City, MX

2015-2018

- Pioneered and founded the company. As a team, we got our place in one of the most important newspapers in Mexico City, El Financiero, as one of the youngest successful companies within Mexico's finance industry.
- Maximized company revenue by being responsible for achieving a partnership with ComparaGuru, one of the biggest online
  travel agencies in Latin America, for offering financial services to people.
- Mentored eight successful financial agents.

#### **EDUCATION**

Coding Dojo | Full-Stack Developer Certificate | Los Angeles, CA.

2022

• Immersive Full-Stack Training Program in Web Fundamentals (JavaScript, HTML, CSS), Python, Java, and MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node)

Escuela Bancaria y Comercial | Bachelors in International Business and Commerce | Mexico City

• Bachelor's Degree: Successfully completed my degree with honors in the EGEL exam.

2014 - 2018